Guide to the Charles Leonard Van Noppen papers, 1881-1935 RL.10025
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles Leonard Van Noppen papers
1881-1935
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles Leonard Van Noppen
RL.10025
9 Linear Feet
Charles Leonard Van Noppen (1869-1935) was a publisher, editor, and author, from Greensboro, N.C. The collection contains letters and papers, mostly relating to the projected extension of Samuel A'Court Ashe's book, Biographical history of North Carolina from colonial times to the present (1908-1925). Collection also contains 356 black-and-white photographs and engravings, almost exclusively 19th century portraits of prominent male North Carolinians.
Biographical note
Charles Leonard Van Noppen (1869-1938) was a Publisher, editor, and author, of Greensboro, N.C.
Collection Overview
This collection contains 250 brief unpublished biographical sketches of prominent North Carolinians prepared for use in a projected extension of Samuel A. Ashe's, "Biographical History of North Carolina From Colonial Times to the Present." Other papers in the collection include printed forms returned by persons from whom biographical information had been requested, reviews of Ashe's Biographical History of North Carolina, an album entitled "Platinotypes of English Cathedrals", published in London by Eyre & Spottiswode as well as personal letters and papers of Van Noppen. The collection also includes 356 black and white photographs and engravings almost exclusively 19th Centruy portraits of prominent male North Carolinians.
Provenance
The Charles Leonard Van Noppen papers were acquired as a gift by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in several accessions in 1957, 1971 and 1979.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Black-and-white photographs; North Carolina -- Biography; North Carolina -- History; Engravings (prints); Samuel A. Ashe (Samuel A'Court); Charles Leonard Van Noppen
- Charles Leonard Van Noppen papers, 1881-1935
  - Biographical Sketches, A-B, 1881-1935 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Sketches, C, 1881-1935 (Box 2)
  - Biographical Sketches, D-G, 1881-1935 (Box 3)
  - Biographical Sketches, H-L, 1881-1935 (Box 4)
  - Biographical Sketches, M-P, 1881-1935 (Box 5)
  - Biographical Sketches, R-S, 1881-1935 (Box 6)
  - Biographical Sketches, T-Y, 1881-1935 (Box 7)
  - Papers, 1881-1935 (Box 8)
  - Photographs, A-H, 1881-1935 (Box 9)
  - Photographs, H-P, 1881-1935 (Box 10)
  - Photographs, P-Z, 1881-1935 (Box 11)
  - Oversize Photographs, A-D, 1881-1935 (Box 12)
  - Oversize Photographs, D-M, 1881-1935 (Box 13)
  - Oversize Photographs, M-Z, 1881-1935 (Box 14)